<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on stochasmos</title>
    <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on stochasmos</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022, swasheck</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 16:21:32 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://swasheck.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Test</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 16:21:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/test/</guid>
      <description>this is a post</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tsql tuesday: preconceived notions (a confession)</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/tsql-tuesday-preconceived/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 13:25:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/tsql-tuesday-preconceived/</guid>
      <description>every now and then i get motivated to type a lot of words that likely make no sense. it&amp;rsquo;s usually an interesting t-sql tuesday topic, and today is no exception. thank you to andy yun (b|t) for the inspiration. this one&amp;rsquo;s short because i dont have the emotional capacity to write a ton, but it&amp;rsquo;s something that i need to get out.
i had a lot of preconceived notions about parenting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tsql tuesday 121: gifts</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/tsql-tuesday-gifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 16:40:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/tsql-tuesday-gifts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to figure myself out &amp;hellip; and I&amp;rsquo;m still a mess, but that leads me to the notion of gifts. There&amp;rsquo;s a common thread in most of these posts - they&amp;rsquo;re not material &amp;ldquo;things&amp;rdquo; and tend to find their location on family, friends, and community. It&amp;rsquo;s encouraging to hear the reverberations of the human spirit throughout the community. I&amp;rsquo;d originally wanted to post something about family &amp;hellip; to post something about those people who are closest to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tsql tuesday: dealer&#39;s choice</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/tsql-tuesday-dealers-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 21:40:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/tsql-tuesday-dealers-choice/</guid>
      <description>The blog is littered with well-intentioned series beginnings, only to see them never truly materialize because I&amp;rsquo;m on to something else. I am a researcher. I am an INTP - a mad scientist and it usually shows. That&amp;rsquo;s a long-winded way of saying, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve not blogged in a long time because I&amp;rsquo;m self-conscious, suffer from a massive inferiority complex, and I&amp;rsquo;ve honestly been busy with quite a few other things.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T-SQL Tuesday, #99</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/2018-02-13-tsql-tuesday-99/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/2018-02-13-tsql-tuesday-99/</guid>
      <description>The blog is littered with well-intentioned series beginnings, only to see them never truly materialize because I&amp;rsquo;m on to something else. I am a researcher. I am an INTP - a mad scientist and it usually shows. That&amp;rsquo;s a long-winded way of saying, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve not blogged in a long time because I&amp;rsquo;m self-conscious, suffer from a massive inferiority complex, and I&amp;rsquo;ve honestly been busy with quite a few other things.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporary Statistics</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/2017-04-07-temporary-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/2017-04-07-temporary-statistics/</guid>
      <description>I am speaking on statistics in June at the Denver SQL Server User Group but didn&amp;rsquo;t really want to rehash much of the same old information that I&amp;rsquo;ve heard in the past. There&amp;rsquo;s a wealth of information about how to interpret stat headers, density vectors, and histograms. There&amp;rsquo;s also been plenty of virtual ink spilled on when statistics are updated (if you have auto update enabled).
One new(ish, to me) and interesting topic I stumbled across is the notion of temporary statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Index Maintenance Operations</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/2016-11-28-index-rebuild-reorg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 18:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/2016-11-28-index-rebuild-reorg/</guid>
      <description>Recently, our index maintenance process was called into question on an Availability Group because it began running significantly longer than expected. The initial theory put forward by other groups was that this was due the Availability Group which is a 2+1 cluster (2 HA synchronous replicas, 1 asynchronous DR replica) and there was a commit delay. Our monitoring tool SentryONE didn&amp;rsquo;t alert us to any significant delays, but we committed to investigate the theory since it would be a good exercise for all involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skewed Data: Analyzing the Windows</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/skewed-data-analyzing-the-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 18:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/skewed-data-analyzing-the-windows/</guid>
      <description>Previously, we looked at analyzing a table to see which columns in that table may contain skewed data.
That was a good start, but now it&amp;rsquo;s time to look at the statistics that exist on that column to see if we can identify potential candidates for filtered statistics, based on the &amp;ldquo;windows&amp;rdquo; between histogram steps.
Much of the logic is the same in this script, except it counts every value in the column.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skewed Data: Finding The Columns</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/skewed-data-finding-the-columns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 17:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/skewed-data-finding-the-columns/</guid>
      <description>While in the process of looking for a job that led to the position that I currently hold, I interviewed for a job at a recognizably-named company that was struggling to keep up with their &amp;ldquo;statistics.&amp;rdquo; I have a confession. I had no idea what &amp;ldquo;statistics&amp;rdquo; were in the SQL Server world. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t offered that job, but in the interim I did a lot of reading and research on the SQL Server notion of &amp;ldquo;statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Value in Incremental Statistics, Pt. 2</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/finding-value-in-incremental-statistics-pt-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 15:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/finding-value-in-incremental-statistics-pt-2/</guid>
      <description>Previously, I did a little investigation into incremental statistics and what benefit they can provide. The goal was to find the intersection of update timings for incremental and non-incremental statistics, with the hope of being able to demonstrate a reclamation of statistics maintenance times - and perhaps higher sample rates. Summary: we can, and auto_stats is a beneficiary. However, is this a solution in search of a problem? If you&amp;rsquo;ve been bumping into statistics maintenance issues, you&amp;rsquo;re probably already familiar with more of the hands-on intervention available (my personal favorite is Ola Hallengren&amp;rsquo;s solution).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Value in Incremental Statistics Pt. 1</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/finding-value-in-incremental-statistics-pt-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 15:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/finding-value-in-incremental-statistics-pt-1/</guid>
      <description>I originally created this post and observed some rather embarrassing sloppiness and miscalculations. I&amp;rsquo;ve simply decided to pull the post and rework it. This is the result of those labors.
Recently, I answered a question on dba.stackexchange related to an interesting occurrence with incremental statistics. This led to an good conversation about the efficacy (and utility) of incremental statistics. The primary focus was on Erin Stellato&amp;rsquo;s confirmation that partition-level stats are not used by the Query Optimizer, thereby identifying a rather sizable gap in the utility of incremental statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server and ReFS: Part 2 - FIO Benchmarking NTFS vs. ReFS</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/sql-server-and-refs-part-2-fio-benchmarking-ntfs-vs-refs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 07:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/sql-server-and-refs-part-2-fio-benchmarking-ntfs-vs-refs/</guid>
      <description>As I was sitting in Bob Ward’s Inside SQL Server I/O presentation, something interesting caught my eye on a slide that noted that ReFS is now supported for SQL Server 2014. I&amp;rsquo;d run into problems with 2012 so I&amp;rsquo;d just given up but this looks promising. I am neither a filesystem aficionado, nor a dilettante but I know that there are some interesting features of ReFS at which Windows server admins are looking to see if it’s viable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server and ReFS: Part 1 - DBCC and In Memory OLTP</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/sql-server-and-refs-part-1-dbcc-and-in-memory-oltp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 04:07:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/sql-server-and-refs-part-1-dbcc-and-in-memory-oltp/</guid>
      <description>As I was sitting in Bob Ward&amp;rsquo;s Inside SQL Server I/O presentation, something interesting caught my eye on a particular slide.

It looks like ReFS is now supported for SQL Server 2014. I&amp;rsquo;d run into problems with 2012 so I&amp;rsquo;d just given up but this looks promising. I am neither a filesystem aficionado, nor a dilettante but I know that there are some interesting features of ReFS at which Windows server admins are looking to see if it&amp;rsquo;s viable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Testing With SQLIO and FIO</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/storage-testing-with-sqlio-and-fio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 20:50:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/storage-testing-with-sqlio-and-fio/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been tasked with testing storage for a hardware purchase for a new, large SQL Server implementation. I&amp;rsquo;ve not gotten everything &amp;ldquo;down pat&amp;rdquo; as far as SQL Server IO methods, but I figured I&amp;rsquo;d take on the challenge of getting better.
SQLIO: The go-to tool There are plenty of SQLIO resources on the Internet, but Jonathan Kehayias has a good post that uses SQLIO well and also references other posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nerf-Herding in Denver (SQL Saturday #331)</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/nerf-herding-in-denver-sql-saturday-331/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 17:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/nerf-herding-in-denver-sql-saturday-331/</guid>
      <description>In the Star Wars universe, the nerf was an adaptable, hairy, slow, grumpy animal that was important for its meat. In SQL Server, the Statistic is a flexible, hairy, (sometimes) slow, grumpy blob that is important in query compilation. The similarities don&amp;rsquo;t end there, though. Both nerfs and statistics can get unwieldy if not managed properly.
I have the privilege of speaking at SQL Saturday #331 in Denver this upcoming weekend (Saturday, September 20, 2014) about managing statistics in SQL Server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Compression Exploration</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/data-compression-exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 20:39:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/data-compression-exploration/</guid>
      <description>I recently wanted to explore potential candidates for data compression in our environment. I found a few ways to go about doing this, most notably this TechNet article that steps through strategy and planning. This was helpful, but I wanted to come up with a repeatable process. Since we have partitioned tables, I also wanted to examine candidates for compression at the partition level for each index.
After conversation with some people whom I consider smarter than I am, I decided that my magic number would be 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filtered Statistics and Tracking Their Use</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/filtered-statistics-and-tracking-their-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 19:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/filtered-statistics-and-tracking-their-use/</guid>
      <description>As users and business activities generate data that is stored in SQL Server, the possibility for data skew increases. For the purposes of this conversation, data skew can be generally characterized as significant variance in frequencies of values in a column. Admittedly, the significance of the variance depends on factors such as data size and/or the informed subjectivity of the analyst. To illustrate, I&amp;rsquo;ll use some data from a recent SQL Saturday (#297) presentation I did on backup throughput analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Saturday #271 - Extended Events In Real Life</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/sql-saturday-271-extended-events-in-real-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 18:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/sql-saturday-271-extended-events-in-real-life/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded my deck and scripts for my upcoming presentation. It&amp;rsquo;s in the &amp;ldquo;Presentation&amp;rdquo; page.
http://swasheck.wordpress.com/presentations/
In order to create the sample &amp;ldquo;Stack Exchange&amp;rdquo; databases, you can use the Gist here .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Tracking&#34; SQL Server (and SQLSat #271 - ABQ)</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/tracking-sql-server-and-sqlsat-271-abq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 23:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/tracking-sql-server-and-sqlsat-271-abq/</guid>
      <description>** Update I’ve noticed some range and scale issues so I took out the explicit schema creation (for now). For right now it just selects into a table, dropping the table if it already exists. **
Back in October I had the opportunity to attend Jonathan Kehayias&#39;&amp;ldquo;SQL Server Archaeology&amp;rdquo; presentation. I&amp;rsquo;d been trying to wrap my brain around Extended Events for a while, but his presentation got me motivated to dive into the system_health Event Session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats Health</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/stats-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 04:24:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/stats-health/</guid>
      <description>I had the good fortune of attending Kimberly Tripp&amp;rsquo;s data skew presentation at the PASS Summit 2013 in Charlotte, NC back in October. In this presentation she revealed some code that she&amp;rsquo;d developed to help analyze skew in your data and make suggestions for filtered stats. This inspired me to take a look at statistics in some of my servers.
So I downloaded her presentation demo and tried to get a sense for what she was doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Backups With Extended Events</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/monitoring-backups-with-extended-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 03:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/monitoring-backups-with-extended-events/</guid>
      <description>This sure has taken me a while to produce. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on it for about a month now. However, I went to the 2013 PASS Summit and have been trying to work through implementing many of the things that I learned there in our environment. Just about the time I got a handle on that, I went on call and the rest has been a blur. Also, sorry the screencaps are so small.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Information on DBCC CHECKs With New Extended Events in SQL Server 2014 CTP1</title>
      <link>https://swasheck.github.io/post/more-information-on-dbcc-checks-with-new-extended-events-in-sql-server-2014-ctp1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 22:22:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swasheck.github.io/post/more-information-on-dbcc-checks-with-new-extended-events-in-sql-server-2014-ctp1/</guid>
      <description>There have been a few blog posts about the new DMVs that are being introduced in SQL Server 2014 CTP1, but Bob Beauchamin has what seems to be the most definitive list of new Extended Events in the CTP. There&amp;rsquo;s no real information out there, though, on how to use them. That&amp;rsquo;s probably because it may be a bit too early, but I like taking things apart so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d check it out.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
